# **Forrest Smith**

Software Engineer with a strong leadership background, interested in front or back-end positions. 2 years experience learning and building real-world software solutions using Javascript, Node.js, React, HTML, CSS, Python, Excel, and more. Flexible contributor with a passion for learning new skills. Strong focus on best practices and exceeding production standards, cemented as a student at General Assembly.

San Francisco **(206) 261 - 8272** 

forrestjmsmith@gmail.com

Github: <u>forrest216</u> LinkedIn: <u>forrest-j-smith</u> <u>forrestjmsmith.com</u>

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **General Assembly, San Francisco** — *Student*

April 2019 - PRESENT

- Built a portfolio of full-stack engineering projects during a 12-week intensive program, putting in 100+ hours a week.
- Exceeded all project requirements, with a focus on code organization, best practices, and UX.

# Fort Point Beer Co., San Francisco — Brewer

February 2015 - January 2019

- Rose to senior production position from the bottom in 2 years.
- Spearheaded complete rebuild of essential production data management software, resulting in a comprehensive network of spreadsheets still being added to and in use today. This environment handled over 1000 new batches of beer with all corresponding yeast, fermentation, and packaging data in the first year alone.
- Organized and supervised initial can packaging system and workforce, launching 3 years of 100+% annual packaging growth.
- Built a can chute to mate with our contracted mobile canning unit using only \$30 in materials. This chute reduced dented cans by ~90% and saved the brewery approximately \$30,000 in labor costs over the course of that year.

## **State Bird Provisions,** San Francisco — *Bar Manager/Server*

January 2012 - October 2014

- Filled multiple positions including admin and floor managing while hosting, bartending, and serving tables at one of the busiest restaurants in the city.
- Acted as the primary host and maître d' through the most intense period of growth, speaking with 100-200 guests each night clearly, concisely, and politely. Managed customer experience and expectations during a time when the wait often exceeded 4 hours for a seat.
- Managed beer and beverage program for 2 years.

#### **SKILLS**

- Experience coding with:
  - HTML, CSS, JavaScript
  - MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js
  - Python, Django, Jinja, Flask
  - SQL, AJAX, Amazon S3 ...
- Strong teamwork and leadership experience
- Seasoned and nuanced communicator
- Critical thinking and problem solving

#### **EDUCATION**

**General Assembly,** San Francisco Software Engineering Intensive

## **PROJECTS**

#### Vintour

Napa and Sonoma winery tours

 Our team built a 1-stop software solution for planning day trips through Napa and Sonoma.

vintour.herokuapp.com

## **Production Tools**

Fort Point Beer Company

- Rebuilt core production spreadsheets with revised functions and calculations.